# MEGAN **MCDEVITT SOFTWARE** DFVFI OPFR

mcdevittbass.github.io/portfolio

415-816-6973

**♀** Greater Buffalo Area (open to move)

in megmcd

mcdevittbass

From practicing double bass to practicing JavaScript, I am always striving to get better. In my 10-year career as a musician and teacher, I have developed my attention to detail, longterm planning, creativity, curiosity, and discipline through consistent self-awareness and growth. I am now converting these attributes to the tech world after completing Nucamp Full Stack Bootcamp with Honors. When I'm not building a React app, learning Python, or playing music, you can find me hanging out with my husband and my dog, Liaeti.

#### Skills

#### PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

**JavaScript** 

C

Pvthon

#### WEB DEVELOPMENT

HTML

CSS

**Bootstrap** 

React

ReactNative

Redux

NodeJS

#### **TOOLS & DATABASES**

Git/Github

Bash

MongoDB

Max/MSP

## **Awards**

Nucamp Coding Bootcamp · Certificate of Honor

Completed 5-month coding bootcamp with honors, for my portfolio project.

## Projects

Thesaurus Chat Bot (solo)

Aug. 2020 to Aug. 2020

This chat bot uses the Merriam Webster Thesaurus API to fetch synonyms to words entered. It was build using BotKit.

- · Wrote code in Node to respond to user input.
- Wrote code in Node to connect to API, tested with Postman.
- · Deployed using Heroku. Tech Stack: NodeJS, BotKit library

Portfolio Site (solo project)

May 2020 to June 2020

Front End Developer

Professional portfolio site to display my projects and information.

- Assessed goals for the project to insure clarity of development and production.
- Created clean design using Reactstrap for optimal readability and ease of use.
- Updated class components to use React Hooks to stay abreast of the latest technological developments.

Tech Stack: React, SCSS, Bootstrap

Five Points Bakery Site - React (solo)

Mar. 2020 to Current

Five Points Bakery, Front End Developer

Refactored HTML site using ReactJS, creating reusable components to display all of the same features.

- Updated the site to React to maximize efficiency and speed.
- · Deployed to Github Pages to show client the product in progress.

Tech Stack: React, SCSS

Five Points Bakery Site - Bootstrap (solo)

Jan. 2020 to Mar. 2020

Five Points Bakery, Front End Developer

Created a new-and-improved website for a Buffalo Bakery including modals, forms, carousels, and a beautiful layout.

- · Met with Five Points owners to asses specifications to give them the results they wanted.
- Designed and implemented most of the site pages and features in an elegant layout.
- Fixed bug in the navigation bar I struggled with centering the navigation bar, until I sought out a better understanding of flex boxes and Bootstrap's use of them. I fixed the centering issue by keeping nav-items consistent sizes via flex-grow and flex-basis.

Tech Stack: HTML, CSS, SCSS, Bootstrap, JQuery

# **Employment**

Megan McDevitt Consulting

Buffalo, NY Mar. 2020 to Current

Design, build, and ship professional quality websites for local businesses.

Buffalo, NY **Buffalo String Works** Jan. 2018 to July 2020 Associate Director

- Managed year-round program planning to ensure processes for efficient/effective operations.
  - · Managed all program data through Airtable bases, ensuring organized, efficient retrieval of information.
  - Designed, created, and distributed monthly newsletters to broader Buffalo String Works community, maintaining brand consistency, to secure donor and community engagement.
  - · Communicated daily with parents from underserved communities, particularly refugee groups.

Site Manager

Sept. 2017 to Jan. 2018

• Assured safety and preparation for program of over 50 students.

Sept. 2017 to June 2020

Planned curriculum and taught double bass in groups to students from 4th through 10th grade, giving them mentorship, new skills, and a sense of belonging.

### Megan McDevitt, Professional Musician

San Francisco, Ann Arbor, Buffalo

Double Bass Instructor

June 2011 to Aug. 2019

Planned curriculum, prepared performances, and regularly maintained double bass studios of 4-15 students of middle school and high school age, providing mentorship and new skills, and clear communication with parents.

> San Francisco, Ann Arbor, Buffalo Sept. 2011 to Current

Prepare, rehearse, and perform in many orchestras, chamber groups, new music ensembles, and solo recitals, most recently with the Buffalo Philharmonic Orchestra

## **Education**

Nucamp Full Stack Bootcamp Certificate with Honors

Jan. 2020 to June 2020

University of Michigan

Aug. 2014 to Aug. 2017

DMA Music 2017

Aug. 2008 to May 2010

San Francisco Conservatory of Music Masters Music 2010

University of California, Santa Cruz Bachelors Music 2007

Sept. 2003 to June 2007

University of KwaZulu-Natal

Education Abroad Program in Durban, South Africa

July 2006 to Dec. 2006